Jean-Luc Mélenchon, the presidential
candidate for Front de Gauche!
(Applause)
(Hear! Hear! )
Dear friends, I guess everybody
knows why we’re here today.
Of course it will not be said that
when one of the peoples of Europe
is suffering under the blows of capitalism,
we, who are progressive
and sincere Europeans,
strong supporters of a social Europe,
of brotherhood
and the union of free peoples,
we’d remain snugly at home,
while people are suffering and fighting
for the bare minimum
that will allow them a decent life.
But listen to me carefully,
it’s not enough
for us to show solidarity.
You have to know one thing: this plan
that is now being applied to Greece,
should our country
run into the same kind of trouble,
would be applied exactly
in the same way to our country.
And this is about to be decided
by the National Assembly
on this coming 21st February.
Do you hear this?
On 21st February
the French National Assembly
will vote on the European Financial
Stability Mechanism
which, if approved,
will lead first to our own submission
to the vindictive and cruel troika
of the European Central Bank,
the IMF and the European Commission,
should the country come to that point,
and secondly,
if this is passed on 21st February,
then the last article of that
European Stability Mechanism
would put into gear
the approval procedure
for the next European treaty
to be signed in March.
Spread the news around!
The outcome of this is being acted
in this country on 21st February.
Put a question to your MPs!
Check whether or not they will be present
on the day of the vote,
because right-wing MPs
and those of the Socialist party
have refused a public ballot
where everyone would vote on roll call.
So it’s your job to check that your MPs
will be present on that day
and to know how they will vote.
The best way of showing solidarity
with the people of Greece,
is to reject here in Paris
the European Stability Mechanism
and to impose a referendum
on the next treaty
that will be submitted
to the Assemblies’ vote.
Thank you all.
Let’s remain watchful, mobilized and
in full support of the people of Greece!
Hear! Hear!
Resistance! Resistance!